Guide to the Percival L. Prattis Papers, 1916-1980 AIS.2007.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Correspondence, 1935-1979; II.
  - Professional Correspondence, 1935-1979; 1.
    - Correspondence, 1969-1979, undated (Box 1, Folder 101)
    - New Material Added, 2011
      - Correspondence from Notable People; Richard J. Daley and W.E.B. DuBois, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1919-1976; 2.
    The Personal Correspondence subseries consists of letters and postcards Prattis wrote to his wife and daughter during frequent trips while on assignments for the Pittsburgh Courier in the 1940s. There is also a folder of letters between Prattis and Rudolph Dunbar, a close friend and an African American symphony conductor living and working in Europe. The letters offer a glimpse into race relations in Europe and the United States. The personal correspondence subseries offers insight into Prattis' feelings regarding the issues of the day. He was a voluminous correspondent and often candid in expressing his feelings. Recently added material can be found under the section "New Material Added." The subseries is arranged chronologically.
    - Post cards to family, 1941-1954 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence to family, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence to family, 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence to family, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with Rudolph Dunbar, 1946-1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence to family, 1956-1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Helen Prattis Correspondence and notes, 1963, 1998, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Condolence Letters to Helen Prattis, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1939-1964 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1967-1976, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - New Material Added, 2011
      - Correspondence in French, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 75)
      - Courtship letters between Prattis and wife, Helen (Sands) Prattis, 1937-1939 (Box 2, Folder 76)
      - Correspondence to Helen Prattis on board the S.S. Argentina on the way to Paris, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 77)
      - Correspondence from P.L. Prattis to Helen Prattis, 1948-1966 (Box 2, Folder 78)
      - Correspondence to Patricia Prattis while at Deerwood Music Camp in the Adirondacks, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 79)
      - Correspondence to Patricia Prattis while atthe Marlboro (Vt.) Festival, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 80)
      - Correspondence to Patricia Prattis during the Pittsburgh Symphony's tour of Europe and the Middle East, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 81)
- Personal, 1916-1980; III.
  This series contains an assortment of materials that document P.L. Prattis' life and career outside the Pittsburgh Courier. Included in the Personal Series is his 1916 yearbook from the Ferris Institute, an honorable discharge certificate from the Army, and the Prattis family's World War II war rations stamp book. There are biographical materials such as his Last Will and Testament, along with obituaries. Also present is assorted writings and copies of speeches, scrapbooks, and photographs of Prattis and his family. Recently added material can be found under the section "New Material Added." The series is arranged by date.
  - Certificate from the Ferris Institute with Prattis' final credit in spelling, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Civil Service Exam Results, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Contracts with Holt Construction for the Prattis Home, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Assorted newspaper clippings on P.L. Prattis, 1943, 1966, 1975, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - War Ration Stamp Book for the Prattis Family, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Loendi Club 50th Anniversary Exercises Program, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Tuskegee Institute material on Rural Housing in the South, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Renunciation, a short story written by P.L. Prattis, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - H-M Club of America Membership materials, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Observation of Jews in the International Scene, speech given before the NCJW Pittsburgh, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Certificate presented by the Group Work Division, Health and Welfare Federation of Allegheny County, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Schlitz Beer Ad featuring P.L. Prattis, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Journey to the Soviet Union, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Appointment to Board of Trustee of Pennsylvania Training School at Morganza, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Honorable Discharge Certificate, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Newspapers clippings on Banquet Honoring P.L. Prattis, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Budget for Pittsburgh Chapter of Frontiers International, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Prattis Household expenses and family budget, 1964-1964, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Writings and Newspaper clippings on YMCA Youth Corps, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Friends or Foes? Forward or Backward? Speech delivered at the Annual Convention of Frontiers International, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - The Newcomen Society in North America, memos and correspondence, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare letter regarding Employment Opportunities Unlimited booklet, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Employment Opportunities Unlimited booklet authored by P.L. Prattis, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Frontiers International, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Draft of story on Martha Brown, Prattis' Aunt, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - YMCA Leaders' Fellowship Certificate, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Certificate of "Outstanding Civic Leaders of America", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - "Cabbie's Honesty Pays Off," Newspaper clipping, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Diary pages and handwritten notes, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - "William A. Arvin: A man without gall- without guile," speech delivered at Arvin Testimonial Reception, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Certificate from Central Baptist Church for work as Black History Instructor, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Certificate of Honor from the U.S. Selective Service, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Certificate of Appreciation from the Moorland-Springarn Research Center, Howard University, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Last Will and Testament and Veterans Administration Benefits, 1975, 1978,1980 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Funeral Service Program, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Biographical Information and Obituary, 1980 and undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Condolence Proclamation from the State of Pennsylvania, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Trees for Israel Certificates, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - "At the Crossroads", undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - "Profile of Robert T.McEnheimer, District Manager with Unity Mutual Life Insurance Company, undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - "Social Justice is the Battle Cry," written for Frontiers International, undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Assorted handwritten notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Notebook, undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - "Insurance and Integration," speech delivered at National Negro Insurance Association, undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - "Some Things to Think About for Economic Advancement," speech delivered to Unnamed Chamber of Commerce, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Assorted Writings, undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - "Complacency, Concern, Frustration, Opportunity", undated (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Untitled writings, undated (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Personal Photographs, 1919-1960s (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Helen Prattis at Cheyney State Teachers College, ca.1930 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - P.L. Prattis aboard the Queen Mary, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Pennsylvania Master of Men Award Presentation Photograph, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Patricia Prattis photographs, ca.1943 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - YMCA Centre Avenue Board of Directors Photograph, ca.1945 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - YMCA Centre Avenue Kickoff Event Photograph, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - P.L. Prattis with wife, Helen and daughter, Patricia on front porch of home, undated (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Photograph at a dinner in Nashville, Tennessee, undated (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Scrapbook, 1940s-1970 (Box 2, Volume 2)
  - "History: Day by Day", 1945-1968 (Box 2, Volume 3)
  - Crimson & Gold Ferris Institute Yearbook, 1916 (Box 2, Volume 4)
  - New Material Added, 2011
    - Army Registration Certificate, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - P.L. Prattis in Army Uniform, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Inscriptions in books (photocopies) from W.E.B. DuBois, Nehru, and Langston Hughes, 1940s (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Democratic National Convention, Chicago -- Employee card and button, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 85)